

# ISAURE DELAPORTE

CONTACT

Email: icmd1@st-andrews.ac.uk

Webpage: https://sites.google.com/site/isauredelaporte

Twitter: @IsaureDelaporte

OFFICE ADDRESS

University of St Andrews St Andrews, KY16 9AL

Scotland UK

# **CURRENT POSITION & AFFILIATIONS**

Jan. 2020-present: Postdoctoral Researcher, University of St Andrews, UK

Jan. 2020-present: Fellow of the Population & Health Research Group at the School of Geography & Sustainable Development, University of St Andrews

Jan. 2021-present: Affiliate of the Applied Microeconomics Research Group at the School of Eco-

nomics, University of St Andrews

May. 2020-present: Fellow of Global Labor Organization (GLO)

### **EDUCATION**

Sep. 2015-Jan. 2020: PhD Economics, University of Kent, UK

Advisors: Matloob Piracha and Bansi Malde

Thesis: Essays on the Economic and Cultural Integration of Migrants

Sep. 2014-Jun. 2015: MRes International Economics, University Paris 1 Sorbonne, France
Sep. 2013-Jun. 2014: MSc International Economics, University Paris 1 Sorbonne, France
Sep. 2010-Jun. 2013: BSc Economics and Management, University Paris 2 Assas, France

Sep. 2010-Jun. 2013: Diploma Law, University Paris 2 Assas, France

### FIELDS OF INTEREST

Applied Microeconomics, Migration, Labour Economics, Demography, Development Economics.

# PUBLICATIONS (peer-reviewed)

- "Interaction Between Childbearing and Partnership Changes Among Immigrants and their Descendants in France: An Application of Multichannel Sequence Analysis" (co-authored with *Hill Kulu*), **Population Studies**: 1-16.
- "The Distributional Consequences of Social Distancing on Poverty and Labour Income Inequality in Latin America and the Caribbean" (co-authored with *Julia Escobar* and *Werner Peña*), **Journal of Population Economics**, 34(4): 1385–1443, 2021.
- "Working From Home Under COVID-19: Who Is Affected? Evidence from Latin American and Caribbean Countries" (co-authored with Werner Peña), CEPR Covid Economics 14 (2020): 175-199.
- "Integration of Humanitarian Migrants into the Host Country Labour Market: Evidence from Australia" (co-authored with *Matloob Piracha*), **Journal of Ethnic and Migration Studies**, 44 (15): 2480-2505, 2018.
- "Adaptation to Climate Change in Bangladesh" (co-authored with *Mathilde Maurel*), **Climate Policy**, 18 (1): 49-62, 2018.

### WORKING PAPERS

- "Family Formation and Employment Changes among Descendants of Immigrants and Natives in France: A Multiprocess Analysis" (with *Hill Kulu*).
- "The Dynamics of Labour Market Polarization in Chile: An Analysis of the Link between Technical Change and Informality" (with Werner Peña).
- "Analysing Childbearing Events Using Machine Learning Techniques: An application of Random Survival Forest to French Data" (with *Hill Kulu*). Submitted for review.



- "Family Trajectories Among Immigrants and their Descendants in Three European Countries" (with Hill Kulu, Julia Mikolai, Chia Liu and Gunnar Andersson). Submitted for review.
- "Ethnic Identity and the Employment Outcomes of Immigrants: Evidence from France" CESifo Working Paper Series 7651, CESifo Group Munich, 2019.
- "The Effect of 9/11 on Immigrants' Ethnic Identity and Employment: Evidence from Germany" No. 353. GLO Discussion Paper, 2019.

#### RESEARCH IN PROGRESS

• "Childbearing and employment of immigrants and their descendants in three European countries: A multistate approach" (with *Hill Kulu*, *Julia Mikolai* and *Chia Liu*).

# RESEARCH GRANTS, HONORS AND AWARDS

June 2019: "Above and Beyond" Award for teaching, University of Kent

Nov. 2018: Grant, Fundación Ramón Areces

Sep. 2015 - Sep. 2018: Graduate Teaching Assistant Scholarship, University of Kent

## SEMINAR, CONFERENCES & WORKSHOP PRESENTATIONS

**2022:** BSPS Conference, European Population Conference, 22nd Demographic Nordic Symposium, PAA Annual Meeting

**2021:** IUSSP International Population Conference, BSPS Conference, UNU-WIDER Development Conference; SASE Conference

**2020:** BSPS Conference

**2018:** SAEe (Madrid); CESifo Junior Economist Workshop on Migration Research (Munich); RES Postgraduate Meeting (London); Postgraduate Festival (Canterbury)

2015: GDRI Workshop on International Migration (Clermont-Ferrand)

# RESEARCH VISITS (including upcoming)

Jan. 2022, May 2022: French Institute for Demographic Studies (INED)

## TEACHING EXPERIENCES

Sep. 2019-Dec. 2019: Teaching Associate, Queen Mary University of London (QMUL), UK Econometrics for Finance (MSc)

Investment Banking Law (MSc)

Sep. 2016-Dec. 2019: Teaching Assistant, University of Kent, UK

Principles of Economics (BSc) Introduction to Economics (BSc)

#### OTHER EXPERIENCES

Aug. 2014-Oct. 2014: Research Assistant, Paris School of Economics, France

May 2014-Aug. 2014: Research Assistant, Innovations for Poverty Action (IPA), Tamale, Ghana

Jun. 2012-Aug. 2012: Volunteer - Communication, Life Project for Youth, Manila, Philippines

## OTHER ACTIVITIES

**Refereeing activities:** Referee for International Migration Review, Journal of Population Economics, Journal of Economic Inequality, Review of Economics of the Household

**Departmental activities:** Co-organizator of the Population and Health Research Group (PHRG) Seminar Series at the University of St Andrews for the year 2022-2023

## **SKILLS**

Language Skills: French (native), English (fluent), Spanish (intermediate). Software Skills: Stata, R, Microsoft Office, LaTeX, aML (beginner).



### REFERENCES

#### Dr Matloob Piracha

Senior Lecturer in Economics School of Economics University of Kent Canterbury, Kent, CT2 7FS Email: m.e.piracha@kent.ac.uk

### Dr Bansi Malde

Senior Lecturer in Economics School of Economics University of Kent Canterbury, Kent, CT2 7FS Email: b.k.malde@kent.ac.uk

### Mathilde Maurel

Senior researcher at CNRS Universite Paris 1 Sorbonne 75647 Paris Cedex 13

Email: mathilde.maurel@univ-paris1.fr

# Prof Hill Kulu

Professor of Human Geography and Demography School of Geography and Sustainable Development University of St Andrews St Andrews, Fife, KY16 9AL Email: hill.kulu@st-andrews.ac.uk

